前情提要...
Previously on The Big Bang Theory...
这是Sheldon的妈妈 Mary
This is Sheldon's mother Mary.
你好
How do you do?
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
还有 当然啦 妈妈
And, of course, Mom.
你好 可恨的悍妇
Hello, my hateful shrew.
你好 老王八
Hello to you, you wrinkled old bastard.
嘿
Hey.
我刚刚收到了美国空军发来的邮件
Just got an e-mail from the U.S. Air Force.
我害怕 如果我回复了 他们就会知道我收到了
I'm just afraid if I respond, then they'll know I got it.
哥们 当你打开邮件的时候 他们就知道你收到了
Dude, the minute you opened that e-mail, they knew you got it.
他们可能正在通过
I mean, they're probably looking at you
摄像头看你
through the camera right now.
天啊
Oh, God.
我觉得有人在跟踪我们
I think someone's following us.
在这里左转 看看会不会跟着我们
Uh, turn left here and see if he turns with us.
为什么在这里转弯? 餐厅在另一个方向
Why is he turning here? The restaurant's the other way.
我也不知道 他有查路况的手机软件
I don't know. He uses that traffic app.
也许前面有事故
Maybe there's an accident.
那就跟着他
Oh, so follow him.
别啊!
Oh, no!
Leonard 如果不介意的话
Leonard, if you don't mind,
我有点累了
I think I'm a little tired.
今晚就到这儿吧
I'm gonna call it a night.
好的 老爸
Sure, Dad.
我累坏了
I'm a little tuckered out myself.
大家明天早上见吧
Well, I will see you all in the morning.
要一起坐车吗?
Would you like to share a cab?
好啊
That would be fine.
- 你住哪儿?  - 威斯汀饭店
- Where are you staying?  - I'm at the Westin.
我也是
Well, so am I.
要一起喝一杯吗?
Could I interest you in a nightcap?
好主意
I think that you could.
现在...
嘿 Leonard
Leonard?
Leonard 你醒着吗?
怎么了?
What?
你有没有觉得我们可能会变成兄弟
You realize you and I could become brothers.
我们不会变成兄弟的
We're not gonna be brothers.
我妈妈也不会给你当后妈
We're not gonna be stepbrothers.
快睡吧
Go to sleep.
但愿如此
I hope you're right.
毕竟一个大男人 和他的哥哥嫂子同住
Because a grown man living with his brother
实在太诡异了
and his brother's wife is weird.
赶紧睡吧
Go to sleep.
好啵
Okay.
你觉得你爸和我妈 会不会正在
Do you think your father's doing unspeakable things
做羞羞的事情?
to my mother?
不会
No.
你这么说是不是因为
Are you saying that
这是一件羞羞的事情?
because the things are unspeakable?
你们的父母都老了
Your parents are old.
他们应该九点半之前就做完羞羞的事情了
Anything unspeakable was finished by 9:30.
赶紧睡吧
Go to sleep.
好吧
Very well.
对不起啊 我也没想到婚礼之前会发生这么奇葩的事
I'm sorry if this stuff is gonna make the ceremony awkward.
天啊 我还以为我哥哥刚从监狱出来这件事
God, I thought my brother fresh out of jail
会让大家觉得尴尬
was gonna make everyone uncomfortable,
- 不过现在...  - 喂 要是你们想让我睡觉的话
- but now this...  - Hey, if you want me to sleep
就别再说话了
you're gonna have to stop talking.
* 宇宙一度又烫又稠密 *
* Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state *
* 140亿年前终于爆了炸... 等着瞧! *
* Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! *
* 地球开始降温 *
* The Earth began to cool *
* 自养生物来起哄 穴居人发明工具 *
* The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools *
* 我们建长城 我们建金字塔 *
* We built the Wall We built the pyramids *
* 数学 自然科学 历史 揭开神秘 *
* Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery *
* 一切由大爆炸开始 *
* That all started with a big bang *
生活大爆炸 第十季第1集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 酥酥要找男票   校对: UU要找工作
翻译: 凤梨酥 李小宝Licht 熊熊
我现在去接我家人
Okay, I'm gonna go pick up my family.
估计得一个半小时或者两个小时 看堵不堵车了
Like an hour and half, two hours, depending on traffic.
- 路上注意安全  - 好哒
- Yeah, drive safe.  - Oh, hey,
哦对了 先跟你俩说好
and do yourself a favor, all right?
Beverly过来之后 谁都别提昨晚的事
When Beverly gets here, do not bring up last night.
懂我意思? 要装作
All right? As far as you're concerned,
你们什么都不知道的样子
you don't know anything,
你们什么都没看见
you didn't see anything.
假装自己是白痴就好
I want you just to play dumb.
其实她亲自给我们示范一下什么是白痴 也挺好的
It was nice of her to show us playing dumb with an example.
你说什么?
What?
呃
Oh.
嗨! 那个 我... 不好意思我得走了
Hi. Okay, hey there, I got... I'm sorry, I got to go now.
- Penny 你等等  - 怎么了?
- Penny, wait.  - Why?
很感谢你不怕麻烦
I wanted to thank you for going through all the trouble
特意为我重新举办了婚礼
of planning a second wedding ceremony for me,
但可惜我不想参加了
but unfortunately I cannot attend.
为什么? 怎么了
Well, why? What's wrong?
什么... 我们还在假装白痴吗?
Wha... are we still doing the dumb thing?
好吧 为什么? 怎么了?
Okay, why, what's wrong?
我实在受不了你爸了
I just cannot stay here while your father
他这么羞辱我实在是太过分了
goes out of his way to humiliate me.
哪有啊 他怎么羞辱你了?
Oh, golly, however did he humiliate you?
别闹了 Sheldon
Stop it, Sheldon.
我是应该说"我没闹"? 还是可以不用再装了?
Do I say "Stop what?" Or just throw in the towel?
我不懂 我何苦要看着你爸
I don't see why I should have to watch your father
对着一个满脑子圣经的村姑献殷勤
parade around with some Bible-thumping bumpkin.
不好意思 打断一下 虽然你说的都对
Oh, excuse me, that is my mother you're talking about,
但那是我妈啊
however accurately.
好了 Beverly
Okay, Beverly,
你太激动了吧?
aren't you overreacting a little?
他们只不过是一起坐了出租车 一起喝了一杯而已
All we know is they shared a cab and had a nightcap.
还都把手机关了
And turned their phones off.
别帮倒忙了!
Not helping, buddy.
妈 Penny和我都非常希望你来参加这次婚礼
Mother, Penny and I really want you to be part of this.
拜托了
Please stay.
是啊 而且如果你走了的话
Yeah, plus if you leave,
Alfred就会知道你在乎了
Alfred will know he got under your skin.
有道理 这可不行
Well, we can't have that.
还有啊 他们要是真的性接触了的话
You know, also, if they did have coitus,
我们就真的需要一个专业的精神科医生了
we'll all be needing a skilled psychiatrist.
仔细想想这事还挺好玩的
It is funny when you think about it.
我可没觉得
Maybe to you.
你是没收到500刀的罚单
You didn't get a $500 traffic ticket.
谁让你开车的时候像个疯子似的
Because you were driving like a lunatic.
以为特工在追你也能被你讲成疯子的话
Hey, if thinking secret government agents
那... 好吧 随便你怎么说吧
are chasing you makes you a lunatic, then... yeah, okay.
我去开门
Oh, I'll get it.
交警抓到你的时候 你都的走不了直线了
It didn't help that you couldn't walk a straight line
谁也救不了你啊
when the cop pulled you over.
我怯场啊
I have performance anxiety.
你最应该知道了 (偶尔怯场表现在性方面)
You of all people should know that.
您好
Hello.
我想找Howard Wolowitz
I'm looking for Howard Wolowitz.
找Howard Wolowitz?
Howard Wolowitz?
这地址应该没错吧?
I have the right address, don't I?
地址?
Address?
他在这里吗?
Is he here?
呃... 不在
Um... no.
你知道怎么联系他吗?
Do you know where I can find him?
我能问下您找他有什么事吗?
May I ask what this is about?
我不能告诉你
No, you may not.
好吧
Very well.
让他给我打电话
Have him call me.
好的
Okay.
Raj 是谁啊?
Raj, who's at the door?
那不是Howard
That's not him.
啊 我都等不及让你见见大家了
Oh, I can't wait for you to meet everyone.
我跟他们说了好多你的事
I told them all about you.
比如?
Like what?
他们知道你哥哥的事吗?
Do they know about your brother?
呃 也不是什么都说啦 就说点像监狱啊 毒品啊之类的事
Uh, not everything, just, like, the jail and drugs part.
你为什么要说这些?
Why would you do that?
- 怎么了?  - 你用不着让全世界都知道
- What?  - The world doesn't need
我们的生活一塌糊涂吧
to know our problems.
好吧 算我不对 但是...
Well, Mom, I'm sorry, but...
嘿 看啊 他们这也有Walgreens超市呢
Hey, look, they got Walgreens here, too.
你真觉得换话题有用吗 Wyatt?
You really think it's helpful to change the subject, Wyatt?
亲爱的 我只是想让路上这段时间过得开心点嘛
Just trying to make this a happy trip, dear.
想都别想了!
Well, quit it!
那个 Randall 没想到
So, uh, Randall, can't believe
这么多年过去 你终于有机会
after all these years you finally get to visit me
来加州看我了
in California.
是啊 幸好我是非暴力罪犯
Well, good thing I was a nonviolent offender,
不然的话我都不能离开本州
otherwise I couldn't have left the state.
好吧 别再说监狱的事了
All right, that's enough jail talk.
Penny知道我在那 她还给我送过烟呢
Penny knows where I was; she sent me cigarettes.
你给你哥哥寄烟?
You sent your brother cigarettes?
他可是制毒贩毒小能手 苏珊
He was cooking and selling crystal meth, Susan,
烟什么的就不要提了吧
I think we can let the cigarettes slide.
别一直在这里唱红脸
Stop trying to be the cool dad;
你可是有一件画着家里的猫的T恤呢
you have a shirt with our cat's picture on it.
既来之则安之吧
Anyway, we're here, slugger.
这下好了 现在他们知道我住的地方了
That's great, now they know where I live.
你在说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
他们一直都知道你住在哪儿
They've always known where you live.
你如果不想被找到的话
Yeah, if you want to go off the grid,
非得搬回你妈妈的房子里不可了
you have to move out of your mother's house.
我们能讨论讨论刚刚我为了你
Can we take a moment to discuss
对政府工作人员撒谎的事情吗?
that I just lied to the government for you?
好啊
Yeah.
我反正是不会为你做到这种程度的
I would not have done that for you.
Howard 就直接打过去问问他想干嘛吧
Howard, please just call the man, see what he wants.
好吧 好吧
All right, all right.
对了
Hey,
一定要说 他来的时候你不在家
make sure you tell him that you weren't home when he came by
是你的印度朋友在你一进家门
and that your Indian friend gave you the message
就把消息转达给你了
the moment you stepped through the door.
喂 你好
Yes, hello. Uh,
我是Howard Wolowitz 给Richard Williams上校回电话
this is Howard Wolowitz for Colonel Richard Williams.
我收回刚才的话 别提到我
Oh, I take it back, don't mention me.
你好 Willians上校 我能为您做点什么?
Hi, Colonel Williams, how can I help you?
什么? 对 他是印度人
What? Oh, uh, yes, he is from India.
不 我不知道他的移民身份
No, I don't know his immigration status.
淡定 我还在等着转接!
Relax, I'm still on hold!
我在
Speaking.
好的 我可以在星期四去找你
Okay, sure, I can meet with you on Thursday.
就定在加州理工吧
Caltech is fine.
我能问问这次会面是关于什么事吗?
Yeah, and may I ask what this is about?
不行?
I may not?
他也是这么跟我说的
That's what he said to me.
给你 妈妈
Here you are, Mother.
谢谢
Thank you.
我很高兴你决定留下来
I'm glad you decided to stay.
你的出席对我和Penny来说很特别
It's gonna be special for Penny and me to share this with you.
我在这真是度日如年
I can't wait for this day to be over.
是啊 特别得不行
Yeah, special, like that.
他们来了
That's them.
千万不要把事情
Please don't make things
弄得比现在更尴尬了
any more awkward than they already are.
那就是尴尬程度小于等于目前状态 明白
All right, so less or equally awkward, got it.
嘿 快进来
Hey, guys, come on in.
谢谢 早上好啊
Oh, thank you. Good morning.
早 你好
Morning. Hello.
大家今天过得好吗?
How is everyone today?
很好 你呢?
Good, and you?
不错 不错
Good, good. Good.
我也不错
I'm good, too.
当然了
Good.
你有没有玷污了我妈妈?
So, did you defile my mother or not?
Sheldon啊!
Sheldon!
你太没礼貌了
You're being rude.
我向你保证
If I may, I can assure you,
你妈妈和我除了拼车和聊天之外
your mother and I did nothing more
什么都没做
than share a cab and a conversation.
你们的谈话里有没有涉及到
Did that conversation include the phrase
"你下面的温柔乡真好看"之类的?
"Your genitals are a joy to behold"?
够了!
That's enough!
我保证 没有任何人说过这种话
Look, I promise you, neither I, nor anyone, has ever said that.
那是因为你不认识他女朋友
You don't know his girlfriend very well.
也没看过我的温柔乡
Or what a joy it is to behold my genitals.
好了 你们先收拾收拾
All right, you guys, uh, get settled in,
然后我们就去对面和他们打个招呼
then we'll go across the hall and say hi to everyone.
真是难以相信我竟然从来没见过Leonard
You know, It's hard to believe I've never met Leonard.
这个嘛 大概是他买小药丸
Well, he probably buys his illegal drugs
都是找当地毒贩子吧
from a local vendor.
这不好笑 Wyatt
Not funny, Wyatt.
- 我觉得还不错啊  - 谢谢
- I thought it was really funny.  - Thanks.
好吧 如果你们都想拿我们的家丑来开玩笑的话
Well, fine, if everyone wants to make jokes about our problems,
我奉陪到底
then I can, too.
咚咚 谁啊?
Knock, knock. Who's there?
我家就是个笑话
Our family is an embarrassment.
- 这不算笑话  - 好了
- That's not much of a joke.  - Okay.
妈妈 我知道你很不安 但我保证
Listen, Mom, I know you're nervous, but I promise you,
没有人会对你或这个家说三道四的
no one is gonna judge you or this family.
对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
但这毕竟是我们和Leonard父母的
It's just we're meeting Leonard's parents
第一次见面
for the first time,
他们都是搞学术的高级知识分子
and... and they're academics and... and intellectuals,
我不希望他们觉得我们是白人败类
and I don't want them thinking we're white trash.
那你还指望他们觉得我们是哪个人种的败类?
Well, what color trash do you think they'll believe?
为什么你觉得我会和一个刚认识的男人
How could you think that I would spend the night
共度春宵呢?
with a man I just met?
谁知道呢 毕竟一个叫耶稣的人说服了你去非洲建教堂
A man named Jesus convinced you to build a church in Africa.
你太弱了
You're kind of a sucker.
什么都没发生 对吧?
Well, nothing happened, right?
一切都结束了
I... It's over.
除非我们结第三次婚
Until we get married a third time,
否则你们俩都不用再见到对方了
you guys will never have to see each other again.
这个嘛 实际上不是这样的
Well, you know, actually that's not the case.
- Mary应该会来纽约看我  - 没错
- Mary may visit me in New York.  - Mm-hmm.
你爸爸也从没去过德州
And he's never been to Texas.
我们可以半路上见
Maybe we meet halfway.
什么? 在乔治亚的查塔胡奇国家森林里吗?
What? In the Chattahoochee National Forest in Georgia?
我不会是唯一一个知道半路是这里的人吧?
I can't be the only one that knows that's halfway.
- 你们不会真的打算
- You're not seriously going
去看望对方吧?  - 为什么不会?
to visit each other. And why wouldn't we?
得了吧 你说这话不过是为了气我
Oh, please. You're just say this to antagonize me.
非也 Mary是个很不错的女人
Oh,Not at all. Mary happensing to be a wonderful woman.
如果气到你了 那只是附带奖励罢了
And if it antagonizes you, that's just a bonus.
Mary 很抱歉让你夹在中间这么为难了
Mary, I'm sorry you're in the middle of this.
不不 不用觉得抱歉
No, no, nothing to be sorry about.
我真的很欣赏你的父亲
I genuinely like your father.
什么? 但他只是个中等水平的学者啊
What? But he's a mediocre academic.
而且根据Beverly的话来看 他的性能力还达不到一般水平
And according to Beverly, his sexual prowess is subpar.
他最多是Leonard的成人版
He's basically Leonard with a bigger prostate.
你是在说我父亲配不上你母亲吗?
Are you saying that my dad's not good enough for your mom?
是啊 顺便连你一起损了
Yes, while also getting in a solid dig at you.
效率可观吧?
Pretty efficient, huh?
这实在是太荒谬了 我去对面了
This is ridiculous. I... I'm going across the hall.
为什么你可以走却把我留在这里
But why should you get to go and leave me here
对付你吵吵闹闹的父母?
with your bickering parents?
好啊 那你走吧!
Fine, then you go!
我也不想和她一起呆在这里 我也走
Well, I don't want to stay here with her. I'll go.
我和你一起
I'll go with you.
那我还是得和这货呆在一起啊
That still leaves me here with him.
慢着 慢着!
Hang on, hang on!
大家都是文化人 这个问题能解决的
We're smart, we can figure this out.
Mary和Beverly不能共存
Mary and Beverly can't be together.
Alfred和Beverly也不能共存
Uh, Alfred and Beverly can't be together.
Leonard和我也不能共存
Leonard and I can't be together.
我可以和Alfred共存...
Now, I could be with Alfred...
但我一看他的脸就来气
but I don't like his face.
有了! 我算出来了!
Oh, here! I've got it!
大家准备好参加婚礼了吗?
Who's ready for a wedding?
真是够了 现在又要从头来过了
Great, now I have to start all over.
你在那个制药公司的待遇怎么样?
So how's the world of pharmaceuticals treating you?
很不错啊 我的业务地盘
Pretty good. I actually just got assigned
刚换了块更好的
a much better territory.
看到努力工作的结果了?
See what happens when you work hard?
她只是个卖药的 我可是要制作啊
Hey, she just sells drugs. I had to make 'em.
够了 到此为止
Okay, that's enough.
谁也不准再说毒品的事了
No more drug talk for the rest of this trip.
说得好 干杯
I'll drink to that.
你还没喝够吗?
Haven't you had enough?
Penny喝得比我多得多
Penny drinks more than I do.
虎父无犬女嘛
Well, I learned from the best.
碰一个!
Aw! Aw!
好样的 Wyatt
Very nice, Wyatt.
现在该明白你儿子这一身毛病是哪来的了吧
And you wonder why this one turned out the way he did.
你看看我每天都遭的什么罪!
You see what I've gotta put up with!
你每天遭的罪?
What you've gotta put up with?
为什么你非得去坐牢?
Why did you have to go to jail?
谁让我被抓了呢 妈妈!
It's called getting caught, Mother!
你好!
Hello!
他来了! 嘿!
Hey, there he is! Hey!
Leonard! 很高兴见到你!
Oh, Leonard! It's so nice to see you again!
我也是!
Oh, you, too!
嘿 你们好 这是我的母亲 Beverly
Hey, everyone, this is my mother, Beverly.
- 你好  - 你好
- Hello.  - Hi.
我们不是白人败类!
We are not white trash!
看到自己的儿子结婚了是不是很激动?
Are you excited to see your son walk down the aisle?
是啊
Yes, I am.
我只是对自己造成的
I'm just feeling a little guilty
这些麻烦觉得特别愧疚
about all the trouble I've caused.
哦 我也是
Oh, so am I.
你今天让上帝都很难过 妈妈
You made God sad today, Mom.
Sheldon 他们没做错什么
Sheldon, they haven't done anything wrong.
我觉得他们相处融洽挺好的
I think it's nice they're hitting it off.
嗯 即使这样也不该这么着急
Well, that's still no reason to rush into anything.
看看我们
Look at us.
我们进展的很慢
We took things remarkably slow.
你和我 两年了我们都没牵过手
You and I, we didn't even hold hands for two years.
其实比听起来火辣的多
It was a lot hotter than it sounds.
你是个耐心的年轻人
You're a patient young lady.
嘿 嘿!
Hey, hey!
她是我的! 冷静点 爷爷!
She's mine! Take a cold shower, grandpa!
为什么他不肯说找你去是什么事?
Why wouldn't that colonel say what the meeting's about?
肯定是坏消息
It has to be bad news.
冷静点 好么? 不要想了
Calm down, okay? Try not to think about it.
你这建议也太蠢了
That's really stupid advice.
你说这话很伤我心
You know that hurts my feelings.
冷静点 不要想了
Calm down, try not to think about it.
好
Okay.
我为啥闲的没事要和你说话?
Why do I bother talking to you?
哦 得了吧 最坏的结果是什么?
Oh, come on. What's the worst that could come of this meeting?
我不知道 他们会把这个发明带走
I don't know. They take the invention away,
而我什么都拿不到
and I get nothing?
好了 那其实没有很糟
Okay, that's not so bad.
你知道参加曼哈顿计划的科学家
You know what happened to the scientists
最后都怎么样了么?
that worked on the Manhattan Project?
政府逼着他们搬到了沙漠
The government forced them to move to the desert.
他们只能秘密地生活 而当奥本海默
They had to live in secret, and when Oppenheimer objected
按着他们的要求完成后
to what they made him do,
他的名声就被他们毁了
they destroyed his reputation.
这个故事你是想说什么?
What's the point of that story?
我刚读了一本讲奥本海默的书
I just read a book about Oppenheimer,
现在是个炫耀的好机会
seemed like a chance to show off.
这才对嘛!
There he is!
(古代犹太)
快乐的希伯来小子
There's my happy Hebraic homeboy.
是的 这笑容我不会忘的
Yeah, that's the smile I'm gonna remember
等你去沙漠之后 我搬过来住的时候
when you're living in the desert and I'm living with your wife.
所以 你是做什么工作的?
So, what do you do for a living?
妈妈 你能回答这个问题么?
Mommy, you want to take this one?
嗯 Randall现在还在待业
Um, Randall's in between jobs.
顺便出庭
And court appearances.
见到你真开心
It's nice to meet the woman
你培养了这么优秀的年轻人
who raised this fine young man.
我很期待见见他爸爸
I'm looking forward to meeting his father.
做好失望的准备吧
Prepare to be disappointed.
他也等不及想要见你
And he can't wait to meet you, too.
我给大家拿点喝的?
Can I get anyone a drink?
好 我可以再来一杯啤酒
Well, I could use another beer.
够了
You're done.
他不想喝了
He's done.
嗨! 大家彼此熟悉了么?
Hey! Is everyone getting to know each other?
一点都没有!
Not at all!
很高兴再次见到你 Hofstadter博士
Nice to see you again, Dr. Hofstadter.
我是 嗯 Leonard的朋友 Stuart
I'm, uh, Leonard's friend, Stuart.
很高兴见到你
Nice to see you, too.
嗨 我是Stuart
Hi, I'm Stuart.
哇哦 我是Alfred Leonard的爸爸
Ooh, I'm Alfred. Leonard's father.
哦! 哦 嗨 嗯 很抱歉 你们想坐到一起么?
Oh! Oh, hi. Uh, I'm sorry, did you two want to sit together?
不 不
No. No.
我还在纳闷为什么第一排会有空座
I was wondering why the front row was available.
好了 我觉得我们可以开始了
Okay, I think we're ready.
人们为什么会在婚礼上哭?
Why do people cry at weddings?
他们在为婚姻里的哭泣彩排
They're practicing for what's coming later.
谢谢你在来参加你姐姐的婚礼之前把自己弄干净了
Thank you for cleaning yourself up for your sister's wedding.
为我的新牙谢谢你
Thank you for my new teeth.
欢迎加入这个家庭 Leonard
Welcome to the family, Leonard.
别借钱给你未来的妹夫
Don't lend your new brother-in-law money.
我们今天聚在这里庆祝爱情
We're here today to celebrate love.
再大点声 怕别人听不见么
Sigh louder, no one heard you.
真的 我可以换个座位
Really, I can move.
不只是Leonard和Penny之间的爱情 还有
Not just Leonard and Penny's love, but the love
我们对他们的爱 以及我们彼此的爱
we have for them, as well as each other.
提到爱 老年人中性传播疾病的比例上升很快
Speaking of love, STDs among the elderly are skyrocketing.
爱是耐心的 但她忍不了
Love is patient, but it's not gonna put up
唠唠叨叨 所以都闭嘴!
with all the side chatter, so let's knock it off!
至少她也换成吼别人了
At least she's yelling at someone else for a change.
说你呢Howard!
Howard!
好吧 我理解大家今天都有点紧张
Okay, I understand everyone's a little tense today,
所以我们直接进入最重要的部分
so I am just gonna get to the important stuff.
Leonard 和你一起站在这里
Leonard, standing here with you in front
站在我们的家人和朋友前面让我有很多感触
of our family and friends is bringing up a lot of feelings.
比如我们上次随性的结婚是多么好的主意
Like what a good idea it was to elope the first time.
还有你真的让我很开心
But also how incredibly happy you make me.
谢谢你和我结婚
Thank you for marrying me.
希望不用再结一次了
Hopefully for the last time.
亲爱的Penny...
Penny...
作为一个科学家，我的工作就是探求事物的原因
as a scientist, my job is to figure out why things happen.
但我从来都没有理解
But I don't think I'll ever understand
我这样的人为什么会和你这样的人走到一起
how someone like me could get to be with someone like you.
你知道... 或许... 我不需要理解
You know... maybe... I don't need to understand it,
我只需要感激
I just need to be grateful.
我爱你 Penny
I love you, Penny.
哦...
Oh...
有人有什么话想说么?
Anybody have anything snarky to say about that?
我想没有
Didn't think so.
我想说点什么
I'd like to say something.
Beverly 我知道我们俩
Beverly, I know that we don't bring out
合不来
the best in each other.
但是我们的感情升华出了很美好的东西
But something wonderful did come from our relationship:
站着的这个年轻人
that young man right there.
我十分赞同
I couldn't agree more.
太美了
That's beautiful.
谢谢 好吧 我们继续
Thank you. All right, let's continue.
嗯 打扰一下 我想说点什么
Yeah, excuse me, I need to say something
给一个对我很特别的人...
to someone pretty special, and...
我实在等不下去了
I just can't wait any longer.
他要求婚了
It's happening.
Leonard啊...
Leonard...
我们一起经历了起起落落
You and I have our ups and downs.
但是我一直把你当成家人
But I have always considered you my family.
即使是担心我们父母像老兔子
Even before the recent threat of our parents fornicating
那样私通
like wrinkly old rabbits.
我不经常表现出来 但是你对我真的很重要
I don't always show it, but you are of great importance to me.
你们两个都很重要
Both of you.
哦...
Oh...
谢谢
Thank you.
好
Okay.
我现在宣布你们正式结为夫妻
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
还有一个附带的室友
And weird other husband who came with the apartment.
谢谢你送我们去机场
Thank you for taking us to the airport.
嘿 我很激动我们居然平安无事地相处了一分钟
Hey, I'm just thrilled we're all getting along for a minute.
是的 我也是
Yeah, me, too.
Beverly 我不想让你难过
Beverly, I'm sorry if I upset you.
往事如流水 Alfred
Water under the bridge, Alfred.
Leonard 你为什么不去拼车专用线?
Leonard, why don't you get into the carpool lane?
嗯 那是个实线 他不能穿
Well, that's a solid line. He can't cross it.
没事 我可以过去
That's okay. I can make it over.
不不 慢慢开吧
No, no, let's plod along.
会让你爸爸心里更舒服
It'll make your father feel more comfortable.
能让我更舒服的是让我知道我早晨一起来
What makes me comfortable is knowing I don't have to
不需要看到你的臭脸
wake up tomorrow morning and see your sour face.
行行好明天早晨别起来了
Do the world a favor and don't wake up tomorrow morning.
差不多一分钟了
That was almost a minute.
车好多呀 我们能赶上么?
There's a lot of traffic. Are we gonna be okay?
航班起飞一小时前肯定能到机场
You'll be at the airport an hour before your flight.
太好了 谢谢你
Good. Thank you.
足够你邂逅另一个老头
Plenty of time for you to meet another geriatric boy toy.
嘿 你不能这么不尊重我
Hey. I will not have you be disrespectful to me.
是的 女士
Yes, ma'am.
Sheldon 你妈妈是个有魅力的女人
Sheldon, your mother's an attractive woman.
你需要习惯这个事实
You need to get used to the fact
那就是男人一定会对她感兴趣
that men are gonna be interested in her.
你好好开车 管好你自己的事
And you need to drive the car and mind your business.
我不能这么不尊重我
I will not have you be disrespectful to me.
什么... 你可不是我妈妈
What... you're not my mother.
不许这么不尊重她!
Don't you be disrespectful to her!
是的 女士
Yes, ma'am.
你会成功的 你只需要再加点劲
You'll get there, you've just got to put some zing on it.
Penny 我不知道我在担心什么
Penny, I don't know what I was worried about.
你的朋友都很可爱
Your friends are just lovely.
哦 谢谢 妈妈
Oh, thanks, Mom.
尽管Sheldon有点奇怪
Although that Sheldon is a bit peculiar.
是么? 我没注意到
Is he? I never noticed.
他让我想到了那只火鸡
He reminds me of that turkey we had
看雨的时候淹死的那个
who drowned looking up at the rain.
警察 警察 别出声!
Cops, cops, be cool!